In math, you can't truly pick things at
random because formulas always give the
same result, which is why computers
don't have true random number
generators. Instead, they usually run an
algorithm on your current local time to
generate numbers that appear random. So,
if we can't pick randomly, how do we
select anything in math? Well, the only
way is to follow a rule of some sort.
So, a rule could be always choose the
smallest thing. For example, if we're
looking at whole positive integers, the
smallest is one. For prime numbers, it
would be two. Easy.
But, what about the real numbers? That's
any number, positive, negative, whole,
fraction, even irrational, like pi or
the square root of two.
Now, try to choose the smallest one.
It's impossible. The real numbers
stretch off to negative infinity.
Even if we try to fix our rule by making
it super specific, like choose the
smallest number after one, we still get
stuck.
There's 1.01, then 1.0001,
then 1.00000001,
and so on.
So, really, what number comes after one?
If we can't begin to specify the order
of the real numbers, next and previous,
first and last, we're stuck.
The ridiculous part is we know we have
infinite options, but despite that, we
can't figure out how to just pick one.
The mission to resolve this began with
one man in 1870.
He took on the task of putting the real
numbers in a definitive order, even if
it killed him.
And, it nearly did.